Guide to the Ta-Chun Hsu papers 14362723
C. V. Starr East Asian Library
Ta-Chun Hsu papers
circa 1904-2016
1938-2008
C. V. Starr East Asian Library
Hsu, Ta-Chun, 1918-2015
14362723
7 Linear Feet 8 manuscript boxes and 4 flat boxes
The Ta-Chun Hsu papers (徐大春檔案) document his personal life and provide a glimpse of his career in China and in the United States. The bulk of the papers consist of correspondence related to his family and his personal life as a Chinese-American and an immigrant living in New York. The correspondence also highlights his relation to a prominent Chinese educator and philosopher, Hu Shih (胡適) and his family. There are also materials related to his father, Hsu Singloh (徐新六), who was a major finance and banking leader during the Second Sino-Japanese War. Also included are immigration and travel documents of T.C. Hsu. Other materials also include news clippings, articles, financial records, printed materials, portraits and photographs, maps and postcards.
徐大春檔案記錄了徐大春在中美兩國的職業生涯與生活以及他的家人和朋友之間的聯繫。信件大部分是他與胡適及其家人朋友的通信紀錄。其中還有與他父親徐新六（Hsu Singloh）有關資料。檔內的信件和照片涉及有關他與家人親戚朋友的關係以及他作為美籍華人居住在紐約的個人生活。檔內含徐大春的移民和旅行證件。其他文件包括新聞剪報和文章，財務記錄，書冊，肖像和照片，地圖和明信片等。
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is located off-site.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Starr Foundation, September 2017.
Arrangement
Arranged by subject and material type. The collection is arranged in 3 series.
Biographical / Historical
Ta-Chun Hsu (Wade-Giles: Hsu, Ta-Chun; Pinyin: Xu, Dachun; Chinese: 徐大春; also known as T.C. Hsu) was born in Beijing, 1918. He was the son of Yang Yu-Hsuen (楊毓璇) and Hsu Singloh (徐新六), and the brother of Irene Hsu (Hsu Ta-Ching, 徐大慶) and Vivian Hsu Jee (徐嘉汝). He attended the University of Shanghai from 1936 to 1938. In 1938, C.V. Starr brought Hsu to America to attend college. In 1942, T.C. Hsu received his Bachelor's degree in economics from Haverford College and his Masters Degree at Columbia University School of Journalism in 1944. He later studied insurance at the Golden Gate College in San Francisco, California. He began his journalism career at the New York office of the Chinese Information Service in 1944. He later returned to Shanghai two years later and worked at the Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury. In 1947, he joined the staff of the Shanghai Commercial and Savings Bank. In 1949, he began working for the Hong Kong office of the American International companies and then in the San Francisco office working for the Marine Claims Department of American International Marine Agency, Inc. and later with the Underwriting Department of the American International Underwriters, Inc. from 1951 to 1964. In 1964, Hsu moved to New York and worked directly with Mr. Starr on various projects at the Starr Foundation. After Mr. Starr passed away in 1968, he began serving as the President of the Starr Foundation until March 1999. He remained as an active Director of the Foundation after retirement. He was a strong advocate for the C.V. Starr East Asian Library at both Columbia University and the University of California Berkeley. On December 27, 2015, T.C. Hsu passed away in New York at the age of 97.
Biographical / Historical
徐大春（韋氏拼音：Ta-Chun Hsu, 又名T.C. Hsu）生於1918年北京。父徐新六，母楊毓璇，姊妹徐大慶(Irene Hsu/ Ta-Ching Hsu)，徐嘉汝（Vivian Hsu Jee）。 1936年至1938年期間就讀上海大學。1938年赴美留學。1942年從哈弗福德學院 (Haverford College)獲得經濟學學士學位，之後入讀哥倫比亞大學新聞學院(Columbia University School of Journalism)，並於1944年獲得碩士學位，開始在中國信息服務(Chinese Information Service)紐約辦公室就職。兩年後返回上海，在大美晚報(Shanghai Evening Post and Mercury)就職。 1947年加入上海商業儲蓄銀行 (Shanghai Commercial and Savings Bank)。1949年在美國保險集團(AIG)香港辦事處就職，隨後1951至1964年移駐舊金山辦事處。他1964年移居紐約，與史帶先生一起從事各種基金會項目。1968年於史帶先生去世後，徐大春擔任史帶基金會總裁直至1999年退休。他退休後仍在史帶基金會並且提供資助給哥倫比亞大學和加州大學伯克利分校的東亞圖書館。徐大春享年97歲於2015年12月27日紐約逝世。
Scope and Contents
The Ta-Chun Hsu papers (徐大春檔案) comprise of correspondence, diaries, news clippings, articles, financial records, printed materials, travel and immigration documents, portraits and photographs, maps and postcards, etc., dating from circa 1904 to 2016, bulk dating from 1938 to 2008. The correspondence contains mostly letters related to his family and other personal matters as well as some business letters. Correspondents include Hu Shih (胡適), Chen Kwang Pu (陳光甫), Li Ming (李銘), C.V. Starr, as well as many of his family members, friends, colleagues, and researchers. The photographs in the collection depict Hsu's life and his family, as well as photographs of Hu Shih. Also include are the Hsu Singloh (徐新六) diaries dating from January 1936 to August 1938 which document his daily activities and notes about important Chinese businessmen and statesmen when he was a major finance and banking leader and a strong backer of C.V. Starr's businesses in Shanghai. Other documents include maps and postcards that T.C. Hsu collected during his travel, as well as caricature, calligraphy, articles and printed materials related to his affiliates.
Scope and Contents
徐大春檔案（Ta-Chun Hsu papers）內含信件，日記，新聞剪報，文章，財務記錄，印刷品，旅行和移民文件，肖像，照片，地圖，明信片等， 廣泛日期為1904年至2016年, 主要文件日期為1938年至2008年。該信件主要含有家信和其他個人事務和商務有關的信件。通信人物有胡適，陳光甫，李銘，史带，以及他家人朋友同事和研究人員等。該檔案中的照片描繪了徐大春的生活和他的家人，以及胡適的照片。其中還有徐新六1936年1月至1938年8月的日記，日記內記載了他當時在金融行業內擔任主要領導人以及他在上海的業務。其他文件含新聞剪報和文章，書法，財務記錄，書冊，肖像和照片，地圖和明信片等。
Conditions Governing Access
Folder-level restrictions are marked in the container list if apply.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. Contact starr@library.columbia.edu for more information.
Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945; Finance, Public -- China -- History; China -- Commerce -- History -- 20th century; Chinese Americans; Immigrants; Banks and banking, Chinese; Chinese American families; Chinese American businesspeople; Accounts; Articles; Bonds (financial instruments); Books; Caricatures; color slides; Letters (correspondence); Clippings (Information Artifacts); Diaries; Itineraries; Maps (documents); Notes (documents); Correspondence; Passports; Magazines (periodicals); Color photographs; black-and-white photographs; Portraits; Research (documents); Slides (photographs); Telegrams; Chen, Guangfu, 1881-1976; Chang, Kia-ngau, 1889-1979; Xu, Xinliu, 1890-1938; Hu, Shi, 1891-1962; Starr, Cornelius Vander, 1892-1968; Shanghai shang ye chu xu yin hang; Starr Foundation
- Series I: Hu Shih Files, 胡適文件, 1938-2016
  Scope and Contents
  Series comprises primarily correspondence, photographs, and other research documents related to Hu Shih (胡適) as well as his family and friends, dating from 1938 to 2016. The correspondence are primarily between Hu Shih, Hu Shih's family and friends, and T.C. Hsu, dating from 1949 to 1961. Most of the photographs in the series depict Hu Shih's social life and family life and events in New York and Taiwan, dating from circa 1921 to 1960s. Also include in the photographs are portraits of Hu Shih and his wife, Chiang Tung-hsiu (江冬秀). The other documents in the series include researchers' writings on Hu Shih, the opening of the Hu Shih Memorial Hall and Hu Shih Park. Additional files are materials on Hu Shih's role in T.C. Hsu's education abroad, correspondence between the Hu family and T.C. Hsu, etc.
  - Biographical, 2016 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Remembering Hsu Singloh, 紀念徐新六, 1938 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Written by Hu Shih, at Lucerne; Photographic copy with envelope sent to TC Hsu from Hu Shih Memorial Hall (胡適紀念館)
  - Correspondence, 信札, 1949-1961
    - 1949, 2 telegrams; 1 news clipping (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1951, 12 letters; 1 telegram; 1 news clipping (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1952, 6 letters; 1 telegram; 1 news clipping (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1953, 9 letters (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1954, 4 letters (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1955, 6 letters (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1956, 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      On Free China Press, Inc. (自由中國日報)
    - 1958, 6 letters (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1959, 3 letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1960-1961, 2 letters (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hu Tsu-wang (胡祖望), to Hu Shih (胡適), January 8 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Restricted Correspondence, 1952; 1 letters (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Conditions Governing Access
      This folder is restricted until 2052 to protect privacy of living individuals.
  - Copies of selected diary entries and letters by Hu Shih, 1938-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chiang Tung-hsiu (江冬秀) on Hu Shih's book collection, circa 1962 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Travel receipts, 1950, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, 照片, circa 1921-1969
    - Portrait of Hu Shih, 胡適肖像, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, sitting on stairs in front of two flags, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, writing, 1959 December 17; 1 photograph; 1 letter (Box 1, Folder 18)
      生日在北[南]溝故宮博物院校[正經注]; inscribed to T.C. Hsu, with letter from Hu Shih to T.C. Hsu about Hsu's travel to Taipei in 1960 January 8
    - Portrait of Hu Shih at age 69, 胡適69歲肖像, 1960 September; 2 photographs (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Photograph of a hanging calligraphy scroll, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
      剛忘了昨兒的夢，又分明看見夢裡的一笑
    - Hu Shih, faculty members and administrators, [Peking University?], circa 1917 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Chung Hwa Studio, Shanghai. 中華攝影.
    - Hu Shih, sitting outdoor, 1957 June 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih and Chiang Tung-hsiu, 胡適與江冬秀, 1957 July 6 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih and friends, 1956 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, in front of building, 1960 December (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, in front of a car, 1961 July (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, at NTU hospital reading the Count of Monte Cristo in Chinese, 1961 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Signed and inscribed to T.C. Hsu, with handwritten note on his health condition at the hospital, dated 1961 April 7.
    - Hu Shih and Chiang Tung-hsiu, 胡適與江冬秀, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Portrait of Chiang Tung-hsiu, 江冬秀肖像, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Portrait of Hu Shih at age 60, 胡適60歲肖像, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Signed and inscribed to T.C. Hsu
    - Hu Shih, Apollo theater, circa 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih and friends, Apollo theater, circa 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, pouring tea, circa 1950-1956 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Portrait of Hu Shih at age 56, 1948 April (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Portrait of Hu Shih, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Reproduction of Hu Shih's portrait from 1914, 1960 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Hu Shih, cutting cake during birthday celebration with family, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - TC Hsu's visit to the Hu Shih Memorial Hall (胡適紀念館), 1967; 3 color slides; 35 photographs; 3 business cards (Box 1, Folder 19)
      with the staff members of the Hu Shih Memorial Hall and the family of Hu Shih.
    - Group visit to the Hu Shih Memorial Hall (胡適紀念館), 1969 January, March; 8 color slides; 6 black-and-white photographs (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Statue of Hu Shih at Hu Shih Park, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Other documents, 其他文件
    - Post cards of Hu Shih Memorial Hall (胡適紀念館), 1975; 2 sets (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Announcement of the Publication of Dr. Hu Shih's Manuscripts, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Hu Shih's 100th Anniversary memorabilia, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Stamps, bookmarks, and brochures
    - International Conference Commemorating the 120th Birthday of Hu Shih, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Virginia D. Hartmann to T.C. Hsu, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Include Hu Shih's verse titled "My Mother"
    - Susan Chan Egan (陳毓賢) on Hu Shih, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Excerpts from A Pragmatist and His Free Spirit
    - Susan Chan Egan (陳毓賢) on Hu Shih, oversized, 2007-2015 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Including articles and excerpts related to Hu Shih
    - Yu-ning Li (李又寧), on Hu Shih, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Chair person of the Board of Directors for the International Society for Hu Shih Studies
    - Articles written by Hu Shih, 1949-1957 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Articles about Hu Shih, 1962, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Incoming, George Kao (喬志高) and others on the reading of Hu Shih's diaries, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Tsu-wang Hu (胡祖望) to T.C. Hsu (徐大春), 1952-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Tsu-wang Hu (胡祖望)'s Memorial Service, 2005 March (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Hu Shih Memorial Scholarship Fund, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - On T.C. Hsu's education abroad
      - Hu Shih to C.V. Starr, 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        Excerpts from Collected Papers of Hu Shih (胡適全集)
      - Burns Brodhead to T.C. Hsu, 2000; 2 items (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Photograph of T.C. Hsu and college friends (Burns Brodhead, Frank Chen), at Haverford College, 1940; 1 item (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Photocopy of Hu Shih notes on Dunhuang scripts, circa 1980s (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Include business cards and publication catalogue from 遠流出版社.
- Series II: T.C. Hsu Files, 徐大春文件, circa 1904-2012
  Series comprises primarily correspondence, photographs, immigration and visa documents, diaries, articles, writings, bonds, caricatures, and so on related to T.C. Hsu and his family, dating from circa 1904 to 2012. The correspondence include family letters, photographs and documents related to his siblings, business letters, and letters between T.C. Hsu and his colleagues and friends. The immigration and visas files document his migration from Hong Kong to the United States during the 1950s, his passports, his visas applications to travel to China in the 1970s, and the permanent residence applications for his siblings. The two volumes of Singloh Hsu (徐新六) diaries document his career as a banker between 1936 and 1938. The five volumes of T.C. Hsu diaries dated between 1943 and 1964. The photographs are primarily portraits of T.C. Hsu and his family, dating from 1930s to 1940s; the photographs also depict T.C. Hsu's activities and travels, dating from circa 1960s to 2006. Other documents in the series include address book, bookmark, articles, calligraphy writing, caricature, fortune telling, financial bonds, etc. collected by T.C. Hsu. The materials document T.C. Hsu's life and his experience as an employee working for an international company and his migration experience from China to the United States during the 1950s.
  - Biographical article, Hsu Ke (徐珂), 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Grandfather of T.C. Hsu.
  - Biographical, Hsu Singloh (徐新六), 1938-circa 1992, undated (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
    Father of T.C. Hsu. Include writing by T.C. Hsu on his father and his attempt to collect archival materials related to his father; chronology of Hsu Singloh; tributes and articles written by others about the death of Hsu Singloh.
  - Correspondence, 信札, 1937-2012
    - Family, 家書, 1951-2008
      Arrangement
      Arranged chronologically.
      Mostly with Irene Hsu (徐大慶) and Vivian Hsu (徐嘉汝) on family matters.
      - 1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - 1952 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - 1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - 1961 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - 1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - 1974 (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - 1977 April, 4 photographs (Box 3, Folder 21)
        Photographs, 照片: Memorial Service of T.C. Hsu's Mother, Yang Yu-Hsuen (楊毓璇)
      - circa 2003-2008, 3 photographs (Box 3, Folder 22)
        Photographs, 照片: Memorial tablets
      - 1976-1978, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 23)
        On family cemetery
      - 1981 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Irene Hsu, 徐大慶, 1937-2003
      - College Diploma and Report Cards, 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - University of Shanghai Alumni Directory and Newsletter, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
        Alma mater of Irene Hsu
      - Incoming, to Irene Hsu, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Outgoing, from Irene Hsu, to T.C. Hsu, 1983-1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Outgoing, from Irene Hsu, to T.C. Hsu, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Estate of Irene Hsu, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Family Friends and Colleagues, 親戚朋友, 1951-1989
      Arranged alphabetically by last name and date.
      - 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - 1962-1981 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - 1977, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - 1993-2014 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
        with notes
      - Bu, Lisheng (步禮生), 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Chang, Kia-Ngau (張嘉璈), 1955, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Chen, Kwang Pu (陳光甫), 1951 (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Chen, Kwang Pu (陳光甫), 1952 (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Chen, Kwang Pu (陳光甫), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Chen, Kwang Pu (陳光甫), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Chen, Kwang Pu (陳光甫), 1955, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Chuang, Linda (永楚), 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        Include 3 photographs
      - Li, Ming (李銘) and Tse, K.K. (謝家駒), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Li, Ming (李銘) and Tse, K.K. (謝家駒), 1958 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Li, Ming (李銘) and Tse, K.K. (謝家駒), 1964 (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Tribute to Li Ming, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Shih, P.C. (史寶楚), 1952, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Shih, P.C. (史寶楚), 1962-1963, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Shih, P.C. (史寶楚), 1976-1977, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Starr, C.V., 1949-1965 (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Photocopy of Birthday Gift to C.V. Starr, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Xu, Zhenhua (J.H. Hsu, 徐振華), 1982, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Yu, C.Y., 1997 (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - Zhang, Zequn (張澤群), 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Organizations, 有關機構, 1969-2012
      - AIG (American International Group), 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
        T.C. Hsu's 50th Anniversary with AIG
      - C.V. Starr Foundation, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
        T.C. Hsu elected as Vice President
      - Dongshan Shiyan Elementary School (东山实验小学), 1998 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Elizabeth Wang Gallery, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Harvard's Archive of World Music, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Hin Lung Yung Memorial Scholarship, Yale University, 2001-2006 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Lin Yutang Memorial Stamp, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Museum of Chinese in the Americas (MOCA), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Metropolitan Museum, Art of Eastern Europe Program, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Suzhou Museum shop project, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Business, 1999-2005, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Medical, 1982, 2001, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Immigration and Visas, 移民簽證, 1939-1981
    - Passport renewal, Visa and immigration application, 1950-1952 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Passport renewal, Visa and immigration application, 1953-1955 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and Applications, Visa to People's Republic of China, 1973-1980 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Application for Permanent Residence Visa, Irene and Vivian Hsu, 1979, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Passports
      - 1939 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - 1945 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - 1950-1961 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Passport photos, 1949, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Certificates of Inoculation and Vaccination, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Hong Kong identification card, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Certificate of Naturalization, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Diaries, 日記, 1936-1964
    - Hsu, Singloh, 徐新六
      - Freedom Diary, 自由日記, 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Silk Diary, 絲綢日記, 1937 January 1-1938 August 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Hsu, Ta-Chun, 徐大春
      - 1943 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 1946 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - 1947 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        Handy Diary
      - 1962 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - 1964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 照片, circa 1950-2006
    - T.C. Hsu standing with siblings, Irene Hsu (Hsu Ta-Ching, 徐大慶) and Vivian Hsu Jee (徐嘉汝), circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - T.C. Hsu on Ellis Island next to the Statue of Liberty, circa 1940s (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Photographic postcard
    - Family photograph, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - T.C. Hsu portrait, circa 1940s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Hsu Singloh portrait, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Irene Hsu (Hsu Ta-Ching, 徐大慶), 1975 June (Box 6, Folder 4)
      Taken during T.C. Hsu's visit to Shanghai
    - Vivian Hsu Jee (徐嘉汝), 1975 June (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - T.C. Hsu in Europe, circa 1960 August; 4 items (Box 6, Folder 5)
      photographic slides
    - Events, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      With Sir Edwin and Kitty Oceten
    - Natalie and Walker Calhows, 2000s (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Photo album, 2000s (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Including travel photos in Switzerland, China, and photos with colleagues, family and friends.
    - Panoramic Group photo, [Shanghai, China?], circa 1930s-1940s (Box 9, Folder 2)
      with Wellington Koo and Mme. Koo in the center
  - Other, 其它文件, circa 1904-2003
    - Address book, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Articles and excerpts, 1950-1988 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Article and notes on Liang Qichao (梁啟超), undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Articles, oversized newspaper, 1982, 1985, 2000, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Bookmark, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
      With poem titled 不老歌, by Zhang Qun 張群
    - Calligraphy, circa 1981-1983; 4 items (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Oversize; dedicated to T.C. Hsu by Bu Lisheng (步禮生, 字鐵生)
    - Caricature, 1989 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Caricature, 1989 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Fortune telling, T.C. Hsu's Bazi (八字), 1965 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Financial: Dividend notice, 1951-1955 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Financial: Shanghai Nanking Railway Net Profit Sub-Certificates, circa 1904; 14 folders 282 sheets (Box 10)
      Issued by the British and Chinese Corporation Limited. Include a letter from [S.Sudka], 1960 November 22.
    - Financial: French Bonds, Emprunt Industriel du Gouvernement de La Republique Chinoise, 1 of 2, April 1914; 7 folders 108 sheets (Box 11A)
      Also known as Pukow Bonds.
    - Financial: French Bonds, Emprunt Industriel du Gouvernement de La Republique Chinoise, 2 of 2, April 1914; 8 folders 128 sheets (Box 11B)
    - F.F. Fraternity profile on Jack Chun (陳正), 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993, undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Include photograph of roses and vase, a 10 Thai Baht banknote, English translation of poem "On a Quiet Night" (靜夜思)
    - Writing on Communist China, Edited Draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Writing on Communist China, Final Draft, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series III: Printed materials, 印刷品, 1930-2006
  Series comprises post cards, maps, ephemera, books, articles, and magazines, collected by T.C. Hsu dating from 1930 to 2006. The post cards depict scenery and buildings of Beijing and Shanghai in 1973. The post card sets, maps, and ephemera were collected by T.C. Hsu during his travel to China and Europe. Many of the books in the series have inscription to T.C. Hsu by the authors. The printed publications are mostly on people that are affiliated with T.C. Hsu and topics related to China the United States.
  - Post cards and maps, 明信片與地圖, 1973
    - Building of Peking, 北京建築, circa 1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Peking Scenery, 北京風景, circa 1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Ancient Building of Tatung, 大同古建築, 1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Memorial of the First National Congress of the Communist Party of China in 1921, 中國共產黨第一次全國表大會會址記念館, circa 1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Shanghai, 上海, 1973; 10 items (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Map of Europe, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Beijing tour map, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Shanghai transportation map, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Shanghai Industrial Expo (上海工業展覽會) Pamphlet, circa 1975 (Box 2, Folder 18)